PERSONAL DETAILS

- (+44) 7539889065
- <u>Naomioalao@gmail.com</u>
- <u>Naomi-alao</u>
- NaomiAlaoDesign
- Bē Naomi Alao
- London, United Kingdom

KEY STRENGTHS

- Leadership
- Management/delegation
- Communication
- Innovation
- Collaboration
- Research
- Critical Thinking
- Time-management
- Problem Solving

SKILLS

- User Research
- Visual Design
- Branding
- Wireframing
- User Flows
- Personas
- Style Guide
- Typography
- Responsive Grids
- Prototyping
- Usability Testing
- HTML
- CSS
- Javascript

Naomi Alao

Curriculum Vitae

UI/UX designer with a background in journalism. Experienced in gathering quantitative and qualitative data and conducting professional interviews. Adept at using motion and imagery to communicate a message.

Recent projects - Developed a language App for iOS and Android operating systems; A web-responsive app focused on personalized travel experiences; A money-saving tool using branding guidelines.

UX/UI PROJECTS

Travel Buddy

Web responsive app

CareerFoundry

Case Study

Jul 2021 – Jan 2022

Travel buddy is a location recommendation responsive web app. In this project, a lot of time was dedicated to learning responsive design patterns, grids, and frameworks for mobile, table and desktop. I also learnt about empathising with the user through conducting user interviews and implementing ideas from the data from design and empathise stages to create user personas, wireframe, and prototypes.

Global Citizen

Web responsive app

CareerFoundry Case Study Apr 2022 – May 2022 Global Citizen is a responsive language learning app. Something unique to this project was that I developed this app for both IOS and Android operating systems. In this experience I heavily referenced Apple's Human Interactive Guidelines and Google's Material Design. This two-pronged approach helped me develop a keen awareness of the nuances in design systems, typefaces, functionality of both operating systems.

Target

Web responsive app

CareerFoundry Case Study May 2022– Jul 2022 Target, another web responsive money saving tool, focused on helping users actualise their monetary goals. A process I learnt in this project was developing brand guidelines to set the parameters of what was in alignment to a brand. This included consolidating Imagery, guiding principles, logo, colours, writing style and typography into a document.

TOOLS

- Figma
- Sketch
- Adobe XD
- **Atom**
- Photoshop
- Illustrator
- Invision
- InDesign

LANGUAGES

English - Expert

Yoruba - Conversational

Korean - Conversational

INTERESTS

- Travel
- Reading
- Technology
- Music

WORK EXPERIENCE

Graduate Technical

Operator

Digital Media Services

lun 2019 - Oct 2019

My role was centred around localising cinematographic content for esteemed movie studios (Disney, 20th Century Fox, Warner Bros, Paramount, Imax, Dogwoof, Eone). On any given day I edited video material, encoded, and transcoded files into a variety of formats, localised content (subtitling and audio playback), finalised international AV content for international online and broadcast distribution and produced edited creative cutdowns.

Assisting editor and videographer

Mary Brown Films

Dec 2019 - Sep 2021

I worked as an editor and videographer for Marv Brown films, an independent wedding and music video production company. My duties include filing and organising source footage, assisting onlocation shoots, setting lighting and audio equipment, capturing behind the scenes, and operating industry-level equipment like gimbals, and stabilisers. During the editing process, I convert the frame rate of the footage, apply creative editing techniques like cutting up footage to the beat, assembling multiple camera angles into the sequence and colour coding the video.

EDUCATION

CareerFoundry,

Remote

2020 - 2021

The University of Sheffield

2015 - 2019

UI Design Program

Intro into UI Design + User Interface Design Immersion + User Experience Design + Frontend **Development Web Specialization**

Bachelor of Arts Honours

Journalism Studies

REFERENCES

Available upon requests.